ripoffreport.com 2018-11-22

# Ripoff Report | Privacy Policy

This privacy policy applies to the Ripoff Report web site. Our contact information is:

Xcentric Ventures, LLC  
Ripoff Report  
PO Box 310  
Tempe AZ 85280 USA  
legal@ripoffreport.com

## GENERAL INTRODUCTORY INFORMATION

We respect your privacy. This is why we have taken the time to disclose our information collection practices and our privacy policy. Please take the time to review this document. **It is important that you understand how we do things around here, and, if you don't agree with these practices, do not use the website, register for a user account, nor sign up for any related emails, etc. It's that simple.**

Protecting your private information is our priority. This Statement of Privacy applies to the website RipoffReport.com and RipoffReportLegalDirectory.com (collectively "Ripoff Report") and governs data collection and usage of such data. By using Ripoff Report you consent to the data practices described in this statement.

## PURPOSES FOR COLLECTING INFORMATION

Collecting information provides not only benefits to us as we figure out new services and develop best practices for the site but also specific benefits to our website visitors and by providing this information, our staff or authorized third-parties as outlined in our Terms of Service can contact you regarding your post or otherwise follow-up if necessary. The following are reasons that we may collect and maintain your data:

  * Verifying Reports as such circumstances or need may arise – Ripoff Report doesn't verify the accuracy of any post nor the legitimacy of any particular author. Please see our Terms of Service for more information.
  * Providing advertising information for products and services that may be of interest to you.
  * Sending you emails that may pertain to your rights (such as information regarding a subpoena for your identifying author information) or to provide you information about news, scams, tips, resources, etc.
  * Website and system administration.
  * Research and development.
  * Preserving social history as governed by existing US law or policy (archiving information in the public interest).
  * Users filing a Report or Rebuttal may opt-in if they would be willing to be contacted by the media, a consumer advocate, or lawyer to help further their cause or to help with an investigation against a business or an individual. Government agencies may contact you as well for similar purposes, however, as per our Terms of Service, providing such agencies your information is at Xcentric's discretion.

## WHO HAS ACCESS TO THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT?

The short answer is certain employees of Xcentric and limited third-party vendors or associates utilized by or connected to Xcentric. Unless you opt-in as mentioned above or as otherwise outlined in our Terms of Service in the section relating to the "Disclosure of Information Supplied by You" which includes our assisting government agencies or other ways that you may lose anonymity privileges, we keep the information within the company. At the same time, third-party vendors hired by Xcentric to assist with administration or maintenance of website systems and/or communications systems may be provided with access to databases and storage that contain such information as deemed necessary by Xcentric. Similarly, we may engage third-party associates to provide you information and products that you may be interested in.

Of the information we do collect, outside of a display name or information that you publish to the public via writing a post, or unless otherwise stated herein or as explained in our Terms of Service, we do not provide our visitors with access to information we collect. People cannot just email us and ask for your information – it doesn't work like that. We might, however, email you on a third-party's behalf. For example, there may be a situation where other consumers are trying to get in touch with other victims.

If you believe that our website has collected incorrect information or if you would like to dispute any information, please contact us using the address at the top of this page.

## COLLECTION OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

Ripoff Report may collect personally identifiable information, including but not limited to, your name, address, phone number, and e-mail address. If you purchase Ripoff Report's products and services, we may in connection with those products and services, create a publicly visible profile that includes your name/company name and photographs. In addition, we may collect billing and credit card information. This information is used to complete the purchase transaction. Ripoff Report may also collect anonymous demographic information, which is not unique to you, such as your age and gender. We may gather additional personal or non-personal information in the future or as published on our website by a third-party.

Information about your computer/device hardware and software may be automatically collected by Ripoff Report. This information can include: your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring website addresses. This information is used for the operation of the service, to maintain quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of the Ripoff Report website.

Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose personally identifiable information or personally sensitive data through Ripoff Report's public message boards, this information may be collected and used by others and we cannot control that data.

Ripoff Report encourages you to review the privacy statements of websites you choose to link to from Ripoff Report so that you can understand how those websites collect, use and share your information. Ripoff Report is not responsible for the privacy statements or other content on websites outside of the Ripoff Report website. Clicking on any third-party link is done at your own risk.

## USE OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

Ripoff Report collects and uses your personal information to provide, maintain, protect and improve upon its products, services, and the operation of its website. This includes, but is not limited to, keeping records of your communication with Ripoff Report and using your e-mail address to inform you about upcoming changes or improvements to our services or that of our affiliates.

Ripoff Report may also use your personally identifiable information to inform you of other products or services available from Ripoff Report and its affiliates. Ripoff Report may also contact you via e-mail or other through other modes of communication with surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current services or of potential new services that may be offered.

Ripoff Report may, from time to time, contact you on behalf of external business partners about a particular offering that may be of interest to you. In those cases, your unique personally identifiable information (e-mail, name, address, telephone number) is transferred to the third party. Ripoff Report may share data with trusted partners to help perform statistical analysis, send you email or postal mail, provide customer support, or arrange for deliveries. All such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide these services to Ripoff Report, and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information.

Ripoff Report may keep track of the websites and pages our users visit within Ripoff Report, in order to determine what Ripoff Report services are the most popular. This data is used to deliver customized content and advertising within Ripoff Report to customers whose behavior indicates that they are interested in a particular subject area.

Ripoff Report will disclose your personal information, without notice, as outlined herein or as described in our Terms of Service. Outside of that, Ripoff Report will disclose your personal information if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on Ripoff Report or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of Ripoff Report; and, (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of Ripoff Report, or the public.

## USE OF COOKIES

The Ripoff Report website may use "cookies" and other technologies to help you personalize your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.

One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. The purpose of a cookie is to tell the web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you personalize Ripoff Report pages, or register with Ripoff Report site or services, a cookie helps Ripoff Report to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of recording your personal information, such as billing addresses, shipping addresses, and so on. When you return to the same Ripoff Report website, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the Ripoff Report features that you customized.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the Ripoff Report services or websites you visit.

## SECURITY OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

Ripoff Report makes efforts to secure your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. When personal information (such as a credit card number) is transmitted to other websites, it is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) protocol.

**CHILDREN UNDER THIRTEEN**

Ripoff Report does not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of thirteen (13). Ripoff Report's Terms of Service require that all users be fourteen (14) years of age or older. If you are under the age of thirteen, you must ask your parent or guardian for permission to use this website.

## DISCONNECTING YOUR RIPOFF REPORT ACCOUNT FROM THIRD-PARTY WEBSITES

As Ripoff Report evolves, and our products, services, and collaboration with other companies grow, you may be able to connect your Ripoff Report account to third party accounts. BY CONNECTING YOUR RIPOFF REPORT ACCOUNT TO YOUR THIRD PARTY ACCOUNT, YOU ACKNOWLEDGE AND AGREE THAT YOU ARE CONSENTING TO THE CONTINUOUS RELEASE OF INFORMATION ABOUT YOU TO OTHERS (IN ACCORDANCE WITH YOUR PRIVACY SETTINGS ON THOSE THIRD PARTY SITES). IF YOU DO NOT WANT INFORMATION ABOUT YOU, INCLUDING PERSONALLY IDENTIFYING INFORMATION, TO BE SHARED INTHIS MANNER, DO NOT USE THE THIS FEATURE.

## APPLICATION

Our Privacy Policy applies to all of the services offered by Ripoff Report but excludes services that have a separate privacy policy without an incorporation of this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy does not apply to services offered by other companies or individuals including products or sites that may be displayed to you in on Ripoff Report or other sites linked from our services. Our Privacy Policy does not cover the information or other companies and organizations who advertise our services, and who may use cookies or other technologies to serve and offer relevant advertising.

## TRANSFERRING PERSONAL DATA FROM THE EU TO THE US

Xcentric is operated in the United States. Information that we collect is, to the best of our knowledge, controlled and processed in the United States. Xcentric does not actively target citizens of the countries applicable to GDPR though people may have used Ripoff Report to complain about perceived wrongdoings of people, and/or in connection with businesses, located in one or more the GDPR countries. Xcentric, through display on Ripoff Report, permanently archives this data as a matter of public interest, free expression, historical research and the exercise of and defense of any potential legal claims.

Xcentic is engaging in geo-blocking efforts due to GDPR and we no longer allow citizens of countries that are applicable to GDPR to user our website. If any citizen of a country that is bound by GDPR is using this site, they are doing so without our consent and assume the risks, including accepting our data collection practices by doing so without any liability to Xcentric. In other words, we aren't going to be liable because you choose to break the rules.

The United States has not sought nor received a finding of "adequacy" from the European Union under Article 45 of the GDPR. Any data that we are collecting and/or processing we deem to be done with your consent; to perform a contract with you; or to fulfill a compelling legitimate interest of Ripoff Report and/or to the public that we do not believe outweigh your rights and freedoms. Xcentric tries to apply suitable safeguards to protect the privacy and security of your personal data and to use it only consistent with your relationship with Xcentric through the use of the Ripoff Report website, it's mission, and the practices as described in the Terms of Service and this Privacy Policy.

Based upon the foregoing, and while we take reasonable measures under US law to protect the data, Xcentric's position is that it not subject to GDPR.

## DATA STORAGE AND RETENTION

Your personal data, and data provided by you about others, is stored by Xcentric on its servers and/or on the servers of third-party vendors that Xcentric engages, located in the United States. Xcentric retains the data **permanently** (although there is a possibility that some data maybe lost due to technological transitions or other accidental errors). This is due to Xcentric's need to preserve historical evidence in the event of litigation, to provide historical data where relevant, including the consumer facing information, to provide information that is of legitimate interest to the public just as court records are and to promote free expression. If you do not consent to this permanent storage of such information, do not use Ripoff Report.

## OPT-OUT & UNSUBSCRIBE

We respect your privacy and give you an opportunity to opt-out of receiving announcements of certain information. Typically such opt-out options are present on the communications sent to you by email themselves. Alternatively, users may opt-out of receiving any or all marketing communications from Ripoff Report by contacting us here:

\- Web page: www.ripoffreport.com  
\- Email: support@ripoffreport.com with the Subject Box Titled "RIPOFF REPORT - OPT OUT/UNSUBSCRIBE" 

## CHANGES TO THIS STATEMENT

Ripoff Report may occasionally update this Statement of Privacy to reflect company and customer feedback. Ripoff Report will maintain the most current version of this Statement on its website, however, because notifications of Statement changes will not be sent out, it is highly encouraged that you to periodically review this Statement to be informed of how Ripoff Report is protecting your information. You are charged with knowing what the most current terms of the Privacy Policy are and by continuing to use the site you agree to the same.

## CONTACT INFORMATION

Ripoff Report welcomes your questions or comments regarding this Statement of Privacy. If you believe that Ripoff Report has not adhered to this Statement, please contact Ripoff Report at:

Xcentric Ventures, LLC  
Ripoff Report  
Customer Service – Privacy Policy  
PO Box 310  
Tempe, AZ 85280 USA  
Tel: 602-518-4357 

Email ALL of the Following:

legal@ripoffreport.com and support@ripoffreport.com with the Subject Box Titled "RIPOFF REPORT – PRIVACY POLICY"

Effective as of 05/24/2018
